

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · KUBERNETES EXPERT

11200 Greenwood Ave N, 34, Seattle, WA 98133

□ (206) 954-1418 | Serstaples@gmail.com | Perstaples | Serstaples | Indicate | Indicate

Summary

Current Software Engineer on the NetApp Kubernetes Service (NKS) team at NetApp. 7+ years experience specializing in Kubernetes, cloud-native engineering, and infrastructure automation. Hard worker who has a penchant for Bash scripts and strong coffee. Interested in helping to shape the future of cloud-native applications.

Professional Experience ___

NetApp Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2018 - Present

- Designed and developed the build system that is the backbone of "NKS" (NetApp Kubernetes Service), a multi-cloud, production-grade, managed Kubernetes offering that leverages several upstream Kubernetes SIG (special interest group) projects.
- · Built Ansible playbooks and provided documentation for the support team to provide services to NKS customers more efficiently.
- Collaborated with front-end team to design an API for the build system and developed it in gRPC.
- · Contributed to Cluster API Kubernetes SIG via Github pull requests and issues, Zoom office hours and Slack discussions.

Drud Seattle, WA

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Operated and iterated on "DDEV Live", a Kubernetes-based web-hosting platform and deployment pipeline for hundreds of WordPress, Drupal, and TYPO3 websites.
- Established and executed strategic plan to honor 99.99% uptime guarantees and service SLAs by implementing self-healing, highly available platform with resource-based autoscaling.
- Instrumented, configured, and tuned observability and monitoring stack using Prometheus metrics and alert dashboard, Fluentd, and LogDNA, with VictorOps and Slack integrations, which provided the foundation for new on-call rotations.
- Re-designed deployment tooling for DDEV Live's platfrom and its cloud infrastructure using Terraform, which automated a mostly-manual deployment process down to a single command invocation.

MedBridge Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / DEVOPS ENGINEER

Jan. 2015 - Jun. 2017; Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2018

- Led effort to move deployment platform from Puppet to Kubernetes, which included translating Puppet manifests into Dockerfiles and Kubernetes specs and adopting technologies such as KOPS, Helm, Minikube, ELK stack, Kubectl, and Calico network policies.
- Reviewed and updated MedBridge services to ensure they met cloud-native best practices.
- · Designed active-active failover system to ensure MedBridge services met and exceeded SLA requirements.
- Built out and managed stateful workloads leveraging AWS-managed services or raw EC2 instances and infrastructure-as-code tooling.
- Implemented cluster monitoring, logging, and alerting system using several open source projects.
- Onboard and remained an ongoing resource for the development team for Kubernetes workflow via documentation, demos, and 1-on-1 sessions in order to ensure developer and application success.
- · Containerized / Dockerized PHP, Golang, and Node applications and wrote manifest files to bring them to life in a Kubernetes cluster.

McGraw Hill Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Built CI/CD pipeline for PHP web app using CircleCl, Docker, Terraform, Vault, and AWS ECS (EC2 Container Service).
- · Redesigned PHP/Nginx Docker images with performance and security in mind in order to make containerized app production ready.
- Contributed various features and bug fixes to PHP web app.

Education

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

B.A. IN ENGLISH LITERATURE

2011

• 3.82 GPA